Hugo Costa

3308 Overcreek Ln Midlothian, VA 23112

Phone: (804)475-2712 | Email: gohucosta23@hotmail.com

Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/hugo-costa-69b793198 | GitHub: https://github.com/gohucosta23

Portfolio: https://gohucosta23.github.io/portfolio 2.0/

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer, creative problem solver and teamplayer, with experience in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Database Theory, MongoDB, MySQL, Command Line and Git. Being a software engineer and learning new technologies is my passion. In a previous career, I worked in the financial industry in a sales team, which prepared me to work in a fast paced environment. With over 17 years of experience I will bring outstanding teamwork and leadership skills to my next team.

Technical Skills

Language : JavaScript Libraries : JQuery,

Frameworks: React.js, Express, Bootstrap, Materialize.

Database: Mysql, MongoDB.

Projects

Salons-R-Us

GitHub: https://github.com/gohucosta23/project Website: https://github.com/gohucosta23/project

- Final project for UofR Bootcamp. Salon booking website that allows Salons, Professionals and Clients sign up for an account to view, manage and set new appointments.
- This was a solo project. I had about 4 weeks to finish the project and It was a great learning experience.
- React.js, JavaScript, Node.js, Express, React-Bootstrap, Multer(picture uploads),
 SendGrid(Send Emails), EmailJs(Contact me email), MySql Database, Sequelize.

Employee-Tracker

GitHub: https://github.com/gohucosta23/React-Employer-Directory

Website: https://employertracker.herokuapp.com/

- This is a simple application that allows Users to track the employees from a given company. Users will be able to see all employees, filter employees by Employee Id and by Role, Sort Employees by First Name and Last Name.
- This was one of the homeworks we had for the Coding Bootcamp. This was one of the first projects we did with React and is a front end only.
- React.js, Javascript

Good-To-Go

GitHub: https://github.com/gohucosta23/project2

Website: https://goodtogo2020.herokuapp.com/index.html

- We built this application thinking about social distancing in the midst of the Covid-19 pandemic. It is a curbside pick up application for a restaurant. Users can sign up, view the menu and place an order.
- This was a group project. I was responsible for the back end, building the relationship in the database, the back end code and the Javascript code in the front end.
- Javascript, JQuery, Node.js, MySql, Sequelize, Express.

Eat-Da-Burger

GitHub: https://github.com/gohucosta23/Eat-Da-Burger Website: https://stormy-taiga-53566.herokuapp.com/

- Simple application allows users to create a Burger and add it to the "devour" list. Once they click the burger as devoured, the burger movies to the "devoured list".
- This was one of our homeworks for the bootcamp. This was an application to showcase the use of express handlebars.
- Javascript, Node.js, Express, Express Handlebars, MySql Database.

Experience

Small Business Owner Got Cleaning

11/2013 - 07/2020

- Communicating with clients, deepening relationships creating more opportunities and from there generating more business.
- Leading a team of employees to overcome challenges and achieve goals.
- Acquire, distribute and store supplies.

Small Business Sales Consultant Bank of America Merchant Services

03/2013 - 11/2013

- Network within communities and partners to find and attract new business.
- Work with a sales team to overcome challenges and meet the banking center's sales goal.
- Conduct meetings with partners to explain policies and operating procedures to ensure functional effectiveness of business.
- Develop prospects from current commercial customers, referral leads or sales.
- Prepare forms or agreements to complete sales.

Personal Banker Bank of America

01/2009 - 03/2013

- Work with clients to identify their financial goals and to find ways of reaching those goals.
- Work with a sales team to overcome challenges and meet the banking center's sales goal.
- Market bank products to individuals and firms, promoting bank services that may meet customers' needs.
- Explain to customers the different types of loans and credit options that are available, as well as the terms of those services.
- Handle customer complaints and take appropriate action to resolve them.
- Confer with customers by telephone or in person to provide information about products or services, cancel accounts, or obtain details of complaints.

Bank of America

- Work with clients to identify their financial goals and to find ways of reaching those goals.
- Handle customer complaints and take appropriate action to resolve them.
- Receive payment by cash, check, credit cards, vouchers, or automatic debits.
- Issue receipts, refunds, credits, or change due to customers.
- Answer customers' questions, and provide information on procedures or policies.

Education

Full - Stack Coding Bootcamp : University of Richmond

02/2020 - 08/2020

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Commercial Technical School

1997 - 2000

This was my first experience in coding when I was in High School. This is a technical high school that teaches students how to code and the principles of Computer Science.